欢迎来到阿富汗
Welcome to Afghanistan.
我的名字是安琪拉亚当斯
My name is Angela Adams.
我是联邦调查局的探员
I'm a special agent with the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
你父亲是法拉兹哈姆札
Your father is Faraz Hamzad.
你的名字是帕瓦娜
Your name is Parwana.
我们听说你不介意给哈姆札制造麻烦
We were told that causing Hamzad trouble wouldn't be a problem for you.
这会给他带来什么麻烦
What kind of trouble will this cause him?
毁灭性的麻烦
The devastating kind.
梅西巴哈矿床
The Meshbahar Deposit.
法拉兹哈姆札发现了它 打算开采矿床
Faraz Hamzad found it. He has plans to exploit it.
我现在正在看 一切都停止了
I am looking at it as we speak. Everything is stopped.
这里有塔利班的士兵
There are Talib soldiers here.
我是来找哈姆札的
I am here for Hamzad.
他不必听你的话
He does not answer to you,
你要叫他出来
Will you be producing him,
还是我来带走他
or will I be coming to take him?
你在这里已经不安全了
It's not safe for you here anymore.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
一个我告诉过你母亲的洞穴
A cave that I once told your mother of.
这是什么
What is this?
她的藏身处 让她消声匿迹
A place she could hide. Disappear.
怎么了
What?
《亡命再劫》
第二季第三集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
安琪拉 别太用力抱他
Angela… just be careful with him.
发生什么事了
What happened?
这么深入这里并不容易
It wasn't easy getting this far.
你们是怎么来的
How'd you even get here?
玛莉安
Marion.
她让我们进来也会救我们出去 一通电话就能让直升机来
She got us in. She'll get us out. The chopper is just a phone call away.
该回家了
It's time to go home now.
如果把他留在这里 他会死的
If we leave him here, he'll die.
也许吧
Maybe.
我们不会这么做
Well, we're not going to do that.
好吧 听着…
Okay. Listen--
我们有很多事要谈 但是一定要送他回家
We have a lot to talk about, but we have to get him home.
他们需要他 他一个人是回不去的
They need him there, and he's not going to make it alone.
我家的人也需要我
I'm needed home too.
因为他和他做的事 你是知道的
Because of him. Because of what he did. I know you know that.
我叫你不要来
I told you not to come.
什么
What?
我叫你照顾雪若和亨利 别管我
I told you to look after Cheryl and Henry, and not me.
小艾
Em.
小艾 他是因为疼爱你才会来这里
Em, he came here only because he loves you.
刚才发生的事则是为了保护我
And what happened just now, that was to protect me.
他知道吗
Does he know?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你告诉他我的身份了吗
Did you tell him what I am?
我说了
I did, yeah.
那你们就应该不难理解
Well, then this shouldn't be hard for either of you to understand.
我不能把他丢在这里等死
I can't leave him here to die.
我要请你们帮我
And I'm asking you to help me.
是时候了
It's time.
你该走了
It's time for you to go.
我们都很清楚
We both know that.
不 我不能在你受重伤时离开
No, not like this. Not with you like this.
你必须走了
You have to go.
官兵正在他家
There's government soldiers in his house.
他们虽然是去找他 但主要是为了我
They've come for him, but they're there because of me.
他们在找的人是我
They're looking for me.
那一家人和那里的所有人都有危险
The family, everyone there, they're in danger.
他们需要他
They need him.
我要带他回去
And I'm going to get him back there.
你们会帮我吗
Are you going to help me?
会的
Yes.
抱歉 搞什么鬼
Excuse me, but what the fuck?
-什么  -我们要带他回家
-What? -We're taking him home?
我们会不会太善良了
Isn't that awfully nice of us?
也许你刚才听到的 和我听到的不是同一件事
Maybe we didn't hear the same thing just now.
他们之间发生了一些事
Something happened between them.
我不知道是什么 也不知道那代表什么
I don't know what it is or what it means.
但我告诉你 我听到的是
But I'm telling you, what I heard is that if we were
如果我们把他留在里面等死 我们就会永远失去她
to leave him up there to die, we'll have lost her forever.
永远失去她 你是认真的吗
Lost her forever? Are you being serious right now?
哈洛德 我告诉你
Harold, I'm telling you,
那就是我的理解 而我不想冒这个险
that is what I heard and I'm not willing to risk it.
所以 没错
So, yes,
我们要带他回家
we're taking him home.
天啊
Jesus.
你很怕她
You're terrified of her.
你本来很肯定她死了
You were so sure she was dead. Was it because
-是因为她没死会更可怕吗  -不是
-the alternative is even scarier? -No.
你不是第一个来找他的人
You are not the first to come for him.
你不是第一个看到机会的人
Not the first to see a moment where there seems to be an opportunity.
当他看起来很虚弱
Where he seems weakened…
我向你保证
I assure you…
他只是外表看来如此而已
he only seems that way.
我对你没什么好说的
I have nothing to say to you…
我的耐心快被磨光了
my patience is wearing thin.
如果他在这里
If he were here…
他会比我更凶狠
he would be far less understanding than I…
我向你保证
I assure you.
如果你有自认为有的影响力
If you had the leverage you seem to think you do…
我现在早就被叫回去了
I would have been recalled by now.
我早就会被逮捕了
I would have been arrested.
那是谁
Who is that?
看来要说英语
English then.
你是情报官员
You're an intelligence officer.
你会说手下听不懂的语言吧
You speak something your men won't understand, no?
你是谁
Who are you?
很高兴你问了
I'm very glad you asked.
这表示你根本不知道自己惹上了什么麻烦
It means you have no idea what you just stumbled into.
你不知道法拉兹哈姆札的生意 对喀布尔有多重要
No idea how important Faraz Hamzad's commerce is to Kabul.
你不知道我在其中扮演的角色
No idea the role I play in it.
不知道你惹了多大的麻烦
No idea how much trouble you are in.
过来
Come here.
政府很担心因为我们上次的转账延误了
The Ministry was concerned because our last transfer was delayed.
你们受到的制裁很复杂
The sanctions you are under are complicated.
我们尽力绕过制裁 但出了点差错
We are doing the best we can to stay ahead of them, but we stumbled.
所以政府允许你来这里骚扰我们
The Ministry allowed you to come up here to harass us because of it,
但这会让他们知道没什么好担心的
but this will assure them there is nothing to be concerned about.
他们利用你来传达信息给我们
They used you to send a message to us.
这笔钱就是我的回复
This money is my reply.
这件事就此结束
And the matter is closed.
你在这里再做什么 你就得负责
Anything more you do from here, you will answer for.
我保证
I promise.
离开
Leave.
你哪来的钱
Where did you get this money?
你不会想知道的
You don't wanna know.
我想知道
Yes I do.
妈 我们现在有更大的问题
Mother, we have bigger problems than that right now.
还有比这更严重的问题吗
What could be bigger problems than this?
你听说过摩根伯特这个人吗
Have you ever heard of a man named Morgan Bote?
他是把丹切斯交出来的幕后主使
He is the one who was behind the deal to deliver Dan Chase.
我们反而抓走帕瓦娜 看来因此而生气的人就是他
And it would seem he is the one who was so angry we took Parwana instead,
他冻结了我们所有的资产 想看着我们就此完蛋
he's frozen all our assets and means to see us ruined over it.
等等
Wait.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
没事的
It's ok.
我只想问你一个问题
I just want to ask you a question.
法路克
Farouk! Farouk!
你要我儿子做什么
What do you want from my son?
法路克…
Farouk…
你最近在这里见过新来的人吗
Have you seen anyone new here recently?
一个女人
A woman…
法路克
Farouk.
好 我知道了
Ok… I see…
这女人不会说我们的语言吧
This woman can't speak our language, can she?
你知道她的名字吗
Do you know her name?
你能告诉我她的名字吗
Can you tell me her name?
法路克
Farouk! Farouk!
你应该把车停在隐密一点的地方
Probably could have parked someplace a little less public.
你想问什么就问吧
Ask me what you want to ask me.
你跟她说了什么
What did you say to her?
你有一辈子的时间告诉她你的说法
You had a lifetime to tell her your story.
现在你却担心我敢告诉她我的说法
And now you're concerned I might have had the nerve to tell her mine.
你跟她说了什么
What did you say to her?
你继续担心吧
You can stay concerned.
我要下去
I'm gonna head down.
不 我没事 我来处理
Oh, no, no. I'm fine. I'll handle it.
-我不认为这是个好主意 -你待在这里我会比较安心
-I don't think that's a good idea. -I'd feel better if you stayed back here.
-好了 听着 -不要
-All right, listen. -No.
你又不知道我要说什么
You don't even know what I'm gonna say.
我知道我现在没办法思考 开头是「听着」的话
I know that if it starts with, "Listen," I can't deal with it right now.
好吗 我知道你在想什么 我们太…
Okay? I know what's going on in your head. We're way too--
怎样 我们太怎样
What? We're way too what?
我本来要说我们太像了
I was gonna say we're way too alike.
我不知道我现在是怎么了 好吗
I don't know what's happening to me right now, okay?
-我希望你能了解 -我了解
-I need you to understand that. -I do.
-不 你不了解 -我了解
-No, you don't. -I do.
不 你无法了解
No. You can't.
但带他回去对我来说很重要
But getting him home, that's important to me.
现在我需要你也觉得这件事很重要
And I need it to be important to you right now.
好吧
All right.
待在我后面
Stay behind me.
我知道自己在做什么
I know what I'm doing.
你当然知道 反正我要你待在我后面
Of course you do. I want you to stay behind me anyway.
现在这件事对我来说很重要
That's important to me right now.
特种部队的直升机
A special forces chopper?
我有个同事对塔什干很有影响力
I have an associate who has influence with Tashkent.
他们会进入阿富汗领空前往你指定的地点
They will enter Afghan airspace, proceed to a location you designate
接三位乘客后过边界回来
to collect three passengers, and return back across the border.
我无法想象你和你同事要付出多大的代价
I can't imagine how much that cost you with your associate.
绝对比你欠我的更多
More than what it will cost you with me.
我说过我没有能力给你任何你想要的东西
I told you I'm in no position to offer you anything you would want.
再也没有了
Not anymore.
你只欠我一顿晚餐
Dinner is what you'll owe me.
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
听着 不管你认为我这次欠你什么
Listen, whatever it actually is you imagine I'm into you for for this,
我向你保证绝对办不到
I assure you, you can forget it.
直升机不会在非必要的情况下
The chopper will not want to be inside Afghan airspace
待在阿富汗领空
any longer than necessary,
他们也完全不想被发现
and they will not want to be noticed at all.
拜托尽量不要引起国际事件
Try not to cause an international incident. Please.
你们也许仍能活下来
You might yet still survive this.
你们不欠法拉兹哈姆札
You owe nothing to Faraz Hamzad…
他的罪行害你们成为目标
who has made you all a target through his crimes.
选择权
The choice…
在你们手中
belongs to you.
如果我们直接打给部长呢
What if we were to call the minister directly?
我们对他的士兵开火
We fired on his soldiers.
恐怕现在打电话也没用了
I fear we are past phone calls.
就算没有开火 这个叫摩根伯特的人
And even if we hadn't, this man, Morgan Bote,
不知怎么地冻结了一切
he has somehow managed to freeze everything.
美国账户 海外账户
The US accounts, the offshore accounts.
我们的钱和承诺
Our money and the promise of more of it
等梅西巴哈矿床全面运作后 会给他们更多的钱
once the Meshbahar Deposit is fully operational
是塔利班不敢轻举妄动的原因
were what held the Taliban at bay.
但是没有钱 我们就毫无防备
But without it, we are defenseless.
本来可以有更好的方法
There had to have been a better way.
如果你当初问我 我就会帮忙找到更好的方法
If you would have asked me, I would have helped to find a better way.
我告诉你 如果我们之中
I promise, if one of the two of us should be angry
有人该为这件事处理不当而生气
about how this was mishandled,
也不会是你
it isn't you.
在她安全抵达前
He didn't want anyone to know…
他不想让任何人知道
until she was here safely.
我懂 真的
I get it. I do.
但是要付出的代价
But the cost of that,
我们到现在还不知道
we are only beginning to know what it'll be.
是
Yes…
待命
standing by…
是
yes…
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
请回到你的位置
Report back to your position, please.
还是没有回应
Still no response…
知道他最后的位置吗
do we have his last position?
再确认一次
Check again!
我在这里
I am here.
原来如此
I see.
如果你在这里为自己说话…
Perhaps if you'd been here instead to speak for yourself…
也许事情就不会如此失控
things wouldn't have gotten so out of hand.
我就说得简单一点
Let me make this simple for you.
你自己现身
Show yourself here…
我会亲自带你去喀布尔政府
and I will take you to the Ministry in Kabul myself…
到时你可以解释那个美国女人是谁
where you can explain who the American woman is…
为何两个美国人想独自拯救她
why two Americans tried to rescue her alone…
还有他们为何应该信任你
and why they should be expected to trust you.
快点决定
Decide quickly…
否则情况只会更严重
or things here will only get uglier.
我们得走了
We must go.
-去喀布尔  -对
-To Kabul? -Yeah.
对你来说不安全
That can't be safe for you.
安全
Safe?
我怎么样不重要
It's not important what happens to me.
重要的是我们的人民安全
What matters is that our people are safe.
-我们得走了 -她说得对
-We must go. -She's right.
如果你这样回去 他会杀了你
If you go back there like this, he's gonna kill you,
然后拿走他想要的东西
and then he's gonna take whatever he wants anyway.
你算老几
Who are you?
凭什么认为你有资格说
Who are you to have an opinion
怎样对我和我的人民最好
of what is best for me and the people I lead?
凭什么认为我该听你的
Who are you that I should account for it?
既然你问了
And since you're asking,
我是竭尽全力确保
I'm the guy who's going out of his way
你不会在回家的路上摔下马死掉的人
to make sure you don't fall off your horse and die on your way home.
如果你以为这样就能让我对你有好感
And if you think that earns you a position with me,
偿还你以为能偿还的债务
that services a debt you imagine might be repaid,
那你就大错特错了
you are terribly mistaken.
-如果我跟你一起去呢  -什么
-What if I went with you? -What?
跟你一起进村子里
All the way into the village with you.
-你为什么要做这种事  -这样我才能化解这件事
-Why on Earth would you do that? -So I can diffuse all of this.
你要怎么做
How on Earth would you do that?
-说实话 -艾蜜莉
-With the truth. -Emily.
无线电里的人想知道 你为什么绑架联邦调查局探员
The man on the radio wants to know why you kidnapped an FBI agent.
但这里没有联邦调查局探员
But there is no FBI agent here.
安琪拉亚当斯已经不存在了
There is no Angela Adams anymore.
发生了这么多事 她怎么可能还存在
I mean, how could there be after all of this?
事实是 我在这里出生 然后被带走
The truth is, I was born here and I was taken away.
这是家族事务
This is a family story.
对你不会造成任何伤害
Nothing that could possibly be compromising to you.
-不行 -为什么
- No. No. - Why not?
塔利班的秘密警察可不是
The Taliban's secret police are not exactly known
会听别人讲道理的人
for their readiness to listen to reason.
我不在乎他喜不喜欢 他只需要担心…
I don't care if he likes it. He just needs to worry that…
他手上的牌比他想的更弱
that he has a weaker hand than the one he thought he was holding.
他会杀了你
He'd kill you.
这是我造成的
I did this.
我打开这扇门
I opened this door.
造成的危险…
And the danger that has resulted--
不会降临在你身上
It will not fall upon you.
我不会允许的
I will not permit it.
你警告过我
You warned me.
你说什么
What's that?
「安琪拉亚当斯已经不存在了」
"There's no Angela Adams anymore."
你警告过我
You warned me.
如果在那个时候
That if I wasn't careful with her
我没有小心应对她
in that moment,
她就会离开我
then she'd disappear on me.
我没想到会在同一天早上发生
I didn't imagine it would happen the same morning.
不 我想她不是那个意思
No. I don't think she meant it that way.
我想她不是在说你
I don't think that was about you.
算是和我有关
It was a little about me.
我横跨半个地球
I just came halfway around the world
就为了拯救一个不想再存在的人
to save a person who doesn't want to exist anymore.
如果早知道这样 你就会不来吗
Would you have done anything different if you had known that?
你真是个混蛋 当然不是
You're such an asshole. Of course not.
但我不喜欢那种感觉
But I'm not thrilled about how it feels.
-我想跟你谈… -天啊 好吧
-And I'm trying to talk to you about-- -Jesus, fine. Okay.
我警告你的时候 你就该听我的
You should have listened to me when I warned you.
这样好一点了吗
Better?
这件事她又没有发言权
It's not like she had a say in the matter.
又不是说发生这件事后 安琪拉亚当斯星期一还会再去上班
It's not like Angela Adams is gonna show up again for work on Monday after this.
我以为也许会有办法
I guess I thought there might be a way
可以保住这个名字
that we would fight to save the name
以某种办法做到
somehow,
因为这对我们两个都很重要
since it was so important to both of us.
我想我是该生气 但那孩子
I suppose I should be angry, but that kid,
她绕了大半个地球
she came halfway around the world
寻找没人愿意给她的解答
to find answers that no one else would give her,
好让她能面对真相
so she could stare the truth in the eyes.
而当我试图利用阶级
And in the moment when I tried to pull rank
让她感到内疚
and make her feel guilty about it,
她却死盯着我 叫我去死
she stared me dead in the eyes and told me to go fuck myself.
你至少得稍微以她为荣吧
How could you not be at least a little proud of her?
他爱怎么说你都行
He can say what he wants about you.
但你教出了一个了不起的孩子
You raised a hell of a kid.
入口被封住了
The entrance is sealed.
前门进不去
There's no way in the front door.
-你必须从… -不
- You're gonna have to go-- - No.
我不要从密道
I will not steal into my own home
溜回自己家
through secret doors.
我要面对他们
I will face them where they are.
拜托不要
Please don't.
我很遗憾事情变成这样
I'm sorry it was this way,
但我不后悔
but I'm not sorry
让你看到这个地方
that now you have seen this place,
还有让这地方也看到你
and it has seen you.
他们会杀了他吧
They're gonna kill him, aren't they?
我们的直升机很快就会到了
Our ride is gonna be getting here awful soon.
如果我们要离开这里
If we're gonna get out of here,
我得告诉他们要在哪里碰头
I gotta let them know where we're gonna meet.
对 你该打电话给他们
Yeah. You should call 'em.
本来不用这样的
It didn't have to be this way.
你大可以让事情简单一点
You could've made this so much easier.
你要跟我走…
Are you coming with me…
还是我们得被迫做你们的人没完成的事
or will we be forced to finish what your people started?
他们不会在这里降落
They won't set down here.
这里太多活动了
Not with all the activity.
我们要翻过这个山脊
We'll hump over the ridge here.
我们有多少时间
How much time we have?
不多了 他们不会等太久的
Not much. They won't wait long.
艾蜜莉 不要
Emily. Emily! Emily, no!
对 计划有变 我们得改变路线 就是现在
Yeah, change of plans. We need to redirect. Now.
你好
Hello there.
能告诉我你是谁吗
Would you like to tell me who you are?
别担心他们
Don't worry about them.
等一下他就要跟我一起走了
In a few moments, he will be coming with me.
他不会为了阻止这件事而害死所有人
He won't get everyone killed to prevent this.
所以 现在
So, at this point,
这只是出于我个人的好奇心
this is just for the sake of my own curiosity.
你是那个被绑架的美国人
You are the abducted American.
造成这一切混乱的人
The one who started all of this mess.
对吧
Yes?
你是联邦调查局的探员
You're an agent with the FBI.
这也是真的吗
This is also true?
如果你告诉我 或许会有帮助
If you tell me, it might help.
我也许会愿意大事化小
I might be willing to make this just a little easier on everyone
只要我不用每天睡觉前 都还在想我不知道什么事
if I didn't have to end the day still wondering what it is I'm missing.
你不属于这个地方
You don't belong here.
这不是你的战争
This doesn't need to be your fight.
告诉我
Just tell me.
你是谁
Who are you?
我的名字是帕瓦娜哈姆札
My name is Parwana Hamzad.
「是谁授权的 」是我授权的
"On whose authority?" On my authority.
对 但如果我们死了你就无法撤离我们了
Yeah, but you can't evac us if we're dead!
这件事我也有责任 照做就对了 明白吗
I'm on the hook for this. Just do it! You understand?
喂
Hello?